Guide to the Pureun records, 2017-2021 UA.31.07.0017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pureun records
2017-2021
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Pureun
UA.31.07.0017
47.4 Gigabytes
Pureun was founded in 2017 for students interested in Korean popular culture. The group performs both original choreography and dance cover from Kpop genres. The collection consists of administrative records, marketing materials, photographs, and video recordings.
Biographical / Historical
Pureun was founded in 2017 for students interested in Korean popular culture. The group performs both original choreography and dance cover from Kpop genres including boy bands, girl groups, hip-hop, and more. Pureun has appeared at events at Duke, including Countdown to Craziness and the International Festival, and regional events like KoreaFest 2019.
Source: Pureun organization site, https://dukegroups.com/organization/pureun, accessed 2019 December 10.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Access copies of electronic records must be accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Provenance
The Pureun records were received by the University Archives as a gift in 2019 and 2022.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of administrative records, marketing materials, photographs, and video recordings. Administrative records include meeting agendas, financial and budget records, and records related to deciding which songs and dances to perform at events. The bulk of the materials are marketing materials, photographs, video recordings. Marketing materials include promotional materials created for Instagram and YouTube, member profile photographs, and logo and other graphic design records. Photographs include member photographs, group photographs, and photographs of rehearsals and performances. Video recordings are mostly of live performances.
Popular music -- Korea; Dance -- Korea; Dance -- Performances; College students -- United States; Duke University. University Archives
- Accession UA2019-0100, 2017-2019
  - Administrative records, 2018-2019; 29 files; approximately 5 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0001)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes photographs and video recordings of a performance at Countdown to Craziness. Also includes photographs of the dress rehearsal and short video recordings meant for social media posts. Photographs in JPEG and HEIC formats. Videos in Quicktime MOV and MP4 formats.
  - Countdown to Craziness, 2019; 148 files; approximately 2 gigabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0001)
    Includes video recordings remaking popular Kpop music videos and photographs documenting that process. Photographs in JPEG, PNG, and HEIC formats. Videos in Quicktime MOV and MP4 formats.
  - Cover videos, 2019; 61 files; approximately 4 gigabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0001)
    Performance video recordings in MOV and MP4 formats.
  - Fallcase, 2019; 4 files; approximately 3 gigabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0001)
    Video recordings in Quicktime MOV format.
  - Fall workshop, 2019; 28 files; approximately 1 gigabyte. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0001)
    Digital photograph in JPEG format.
  - Group photograph, 2018-2019; 1 file; less than 1 megabyte (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0001)
    Digital photographs in HEIC and JPEG formats.
  - Halloween photographs, 2019; 50 files; approximately 75 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0001)
    Includes photographs of practices, as well as photographs and video recordings of a performance at Homecoming. Digital photographs in HEIC and JPEG formats. Videos in MP4 and Quicktime MOV formats.
  - Homecoming, 2019; 130 files; approximately 1 gigabyte. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0001)
    Includes photographs and video recordings of a community meal. Photographs in HEIC, JPEG, and PNG formats. Videos in Quicktime, and MP4 formats.
  - Hot Pot + Hot Seat, 2019; 44 files; approximately 200 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
    Includes the performance entry video recording and photographs of the group's trip to Kfest. Photographs in HEIC and JPEG formats. Videos in MP4 and Quicktime MOV formats.
  - Kfest, 2019; 126 files; approximatley 500 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
    Includes logo and other graphic design materials, video recordings made for Instagram and Youtube, and related public relations materials. Images in PNG, PSD, JPEG, and HEIC formats. Videos in MP4 and Quicktime MOV formats. Document files in PDF format.
  - Marketing, 2018-2019; 124 files; approximately 8 gigabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
    Includes photographs of Pureun members at the Nasher Museum of Art. Photographs in JPEG and HEIC formats.
  - Nasher brunch, 2019; 31 files; approximately 50 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
    Includes photographs and video recordings of members informing new members of their successful audition. Photographs in JPEG and HEIC formats. Videos in Quicktime MOV and MP4 formats.
  - Newbie Welcome, 2019; 107 files; approximatley 1 gigabyte. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
    Includes photographs of individual members for use in marketing purposes. Images in JPEG format.
  - Pureun photoshoot, 2019; 41 files; approximatley 75 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
  - Pureun x DCD collaboration, 2019; 16 files; approximately 1 gigabyte. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
    Document file in MS Word format.
  - Showcase ideas, 2019; 1 file; less than 1 megabyte (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
    Photographs in HEIC format.
  - Spring workshop photographs, 2019; 2 files; approximately 5 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
    Video recordings in MP4 format.
  - Unidentified performance, 2017-2018; 3 files; approximately 30 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070007-SET-0002)
- Accession UA2022-0010, 2019-2021
  - 2018-2019 records, 2019-2020; Approximately 80 fles; 875 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
    Includes still image, audiovisual, and document files.
  - 2019-2020 records, Approximately 200 files; 20 gigabytes (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
  - 2020-2021 records, Approximately 25 files; 3 gigabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
    Includes audiovisual and document files.
  - Agenda, 2020; 1 file; less than 1 megabyte (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
    Contains a document file.
  - COVER VIDEOS, 2019-2020; Approximately 10 files; 100 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
    Includes still image and audiovisual files.
  - IMPORTANT_admin info, 2019-2021; Approximately 5 files; 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
    Contains document files.
  - Marketing, 2019-2021; Approximately 30 files; 100 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
    Includes still images and audiovisual files.
  - Pureun Youtube Videos, 2021; Approximately 10 files; 400 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
    Contains audiovisual files.
  - Showcase, 2019-2021; Approximately 15 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
  - Treasury, 2020-2021; Approximately 25 files; 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)
    Includes document and still image files.
  - Vlogs, 2020; Approximately 5 files; 200 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA31070017-SET-0003)